# Wey Gu Software Developer



# About me

Working on OpenStack related development stuff at Ericsson, based in Shanghai, I like building things and troubleshooting to solve challenging problems. I am open to opportunities for building good things with great guys.

I grew up in China (Mandarin) and had worked globally for remote and onsite (English).

### Skills

Python

OpenStack

**FullStack** 

Linux

#### Contact



Changning, 88 Huichuan Rd.



weyl.gu@gmail.com



(86) 150-4242-7363



https://note.siwei.info



🔂 wey-gu



# Experience

# Senior System Engineer

Ericsson

Since Aug. 2018

System Engineer and Developer at Cloud R&D, System & Technology Unit, Core Team.

# **Cloud Engineer**

Ericsson

Sept. 2016 - Aug. 2018

Cloud Troubleshooter for global customers. Tier 3 Support/Troubleshoot on OpenStack for half a year. Tool/DevOps Developer.

#### Telco. Integration Engineer

Ericsson

June 2011 - Sept. 2016

Integration & verification on circuit switch core network (3G), Tool Developer.



#### Education

#### **Bachelor of Mathematics**

September 2007 - June 2011

Majored in Math & Applied Math, Dalian University of Technology.

# <>> Projects

#### **Resource Board**

Vue, Flask, PostgreSQL, K8s, Redis

Side Project, a scalable web app built with Flask socketio & Vue.is. Targeting to build a webapp for fun yet helping improve distributed team collaboration. WIP.

# Cloud ML-**ResourceOpt**

Bayesian Optimization, Heat, Ansible, AlOps Side Project, a PoC on using ML(BO) to help optimize given benchmark and OpenStack environment. It is aiming to output a toolchain and methodology on the scenario is the

optimizing the OpenStack System, where, in the PoC, resource placement weighing policy. This PoC leveraged statistical auto-ML method and DevOps tooling to decouple Telco. domain expertise, reduce expensive experiment epochs in orders of magnitude to enable 10+% perf. improvement in 48 hours of auto learning.

#### Telco. laaS

OpenStack My daytime work, System Design and SW Developer

on Telco. Cloud Infra System, troubleshoot and Requirement Study/ System and Feature Design/ Development. Core team member.